Willis Britton papers D.370 D.370
University of Rochester
Willis Britton papers
1845- 1982
University of Rochester Rush Rhees Library 500 Joseph C. Wilson Blvd Rochester, New York 14627 rchives@library.rochester.edu http://www.library.rochester.edu
Britton, Willis, 1860-1935
D.370
.5 Cubic feet (1 container)
Biographical/Historical note
Willis Nelson Britton was born June 6, 1860 in Greece, New York. He was the son of Alanson P. and Laura Lewis Britton. On January 12, 1885, he married Charlotte Lottie Ann Combs in Batavia, New York. They had four children: Hervey (1885-1962), Laura (1889-1952), Nelson "Ward" (1892-1956), and Avis (1896-1989). Britton ran a produce business in Rochester, New York and founded the W.N. Britton Realty Company, which was a developer of Greece, New York. He died February 8, 1935.
Scope and Contents note
The Willis Britton Papers contains two series: Personal Papers and Business Materials. Personal Papers include photographs, maps, legal documents, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and genealogical material relating to his business affairs and family. Business Materials documents the developing of W.N. Britton Reality Company.
Restrictions on Access
The Willis Britton Papers is open for research use. Researchers are advised to contact the Rare Books Special Collections & Preservation Department prior to visiting. Upon arrival, researchers will also be asked to fill out a registration form and provide photo identification.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Willis Britton Papers were the gift of his granddaughter, Carol Miller Reed, on August 25, 1997.
Photographs; Maps; Legal instruments; Correspondence; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); New York (State)--Greece; Britton, Willis, 1860-1935; W.N. Britton Realty Company
- Series I: Personal papers
  - Alanson P. Britton notebook, 1851-1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Britton family: Genealogy and signatures, 1755-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Declaration of intention to preserve restrictions on use of land, 1961-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Estate of Charlotte (Lottie) Britton, 1939-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Greece, New York: History of, 1955-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hoover Drive School, 1971-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hoover School contract: Britton property, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Maps and deeds, 1920-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Avis Britton: Oral history interview, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Britton family (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Britton residences (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Britton residence, 1549 Dewey Avenue, 1912-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Britton residence, 1587 Dewey Avenue, 1907-1912 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Driving Park Hotel, 1902-1906 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: St. Petersburg, Florida (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Commemoration of Erie Canal and the New England Pioneers Program, March 10, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II: Business materials
  - W.N. and A.P. Britton: Produce business, 1857-1909 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - W.N. Britton Realty Company, 1908-1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Certificate of membership of the Fire Department, City of Rochester for Alanson. P. Britton, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Boat rules for Troy Ohio Detroit and New-York Ohio lines, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 20)